<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>From ChromeDome to your dome.</title>
    <description>Lessons learned while trying to improve my own life. I fix tech, I break tech I build tech, I teach tech. Whatever it takes. InfoSec, coding, hacking, WebAppSec,  micro-electronics, ham radio, teaching. If it isn&#39;t here, I won&#39;t  remember it.
</description>
    <link>http://robie1373.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://robie1373.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 23:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 23:22:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stunnel SSH for fun or profit.</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;stunnel-ssh-for-fun-or-profit-but-not-both&quot;&gt;Stunnel SSH for fun or profit. (but not both)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a decent writeup for getting set up on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unixmen.com/tunnel-ssh0connections-ssl-using-stunnel-debian-7-ubuntu-13-10/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m using OS X for one end of my experiment so there are some differences. Brew only seems to have stunnel3 for example while they are using 4. There are some differences in configuration at the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some fiddling (make sure you don’t copy the wrong cert to the server…) the test works. As expected, the thing resetting ssh was no match for SSL tunneling. Go team proxy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what I had to do differently from the guide above:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://robie1373.github.io/hacking,/network/2016/01/19/stunnel-for-ssh.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://robie1373.github.io/hacking,/network/2016/01/19/stunnel-for-ssh.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>hacking,</category>
        
        <category>network</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>RFL: Software with good cloud solutions</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;software-i-used-to-run-locally-that-i-can-now-run-in-the-cloud&quot;&gt;Software I used to run locally that I can now run in the cloud&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hosted solutions are a pretty good compromise for this project. It pretty much depends on solid Intertube connection all the time, so the concern of working offline is basically ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the tools I am replacing and what they are being replaced with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Tool&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Cloud replacement&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Cost&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Arduino&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://codebender.cc/&quot;&gt;Codebender&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Free&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Storage&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Google Drive&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Free for 2 years&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://robie1373.github.io/hacking,/infrastructure/2016/01/19/RLF-cloud-solutions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://robie1373.github.io/hacking,/infrastructure/2016/01/19/RLF-cloud-solutions.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>hacking,</category>
        
        <category>infrastructure</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hardening VPS</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;hardening-vps-hosts&quot;&gt;Hardening VPS hosts.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’m using all kinds of VPS hosts, I want to streamline the hardening 
process. For now, the folks at Digital Ocean have some very good checklists
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/initial-server-setup-with-ubuntu-14-04&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow up with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/additional-recommended-steps-for-new-ubuntu-14-04-servers&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://robie1373.github.io/hacking,/infrastructure/2016/01/18/vps-hardening.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://robie1373.github.io/hacking,/infrastructure/2016/01/18/vps-hardening.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>hacking,</category>
        
        <category>infrastructure</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Installing Docker on chromebook</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-was-not-apparent-to-me&quot;&gt;What was not apparent to me…&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Apt-get install docker.io
# [output]
# sudo docker -d -D 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last line starts the docker deamon. Don’t even bother trying to use service… yet. I think that can be used to make it run as an actual daemon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m encountering some issues building an image on the CB. Preliminary investigations indicate it may be related to the kernel configuration (which I haven’t found yet).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://robie1373.github.io/robie,/hacking,/infrastructure/2016/01/18/setting-up-docker-on-chromebook.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://robie1373.github.io/robie,/hacking,/infrastructure/2016/01/18/setting-up-docker-on-chromebook.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Robie,</category>
        
        <category>hacking,</category>
        
        <category>infrastructure</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I use vim</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-i-use-vim&quot;&gt;How I use Vim&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep my .vim in github. I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tpope/vim-pathogen&quot;&gt;pathogen&lt;/a&gt; to handle plugins, which I’m trying to keep to a minimum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I get to a new box I&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;localhost:~ git clone https://github.com/robie1373/vim
localhost:~ cd vim/bundle
localhost:~ for rep in `cat ../packages_list.txt` ; do git clone $rep ; done
localhost:~ cd .. ; ln -s vimrc ~/.vimrc
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I just have to remember to git pull from time to time and push any changes I make back up to GH. I have been super happy with this arrangement since I got those habits built up.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://robie1373.github.io/robie,/hacking/2016/01/18/how-i-use-vim.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://robie1373.github.io/robie,/hacking/2016/01/18/how-i-use-vim.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Robie,</category>
        
        <category>hacking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using crouton to enble the RLF process</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;using-crouton-to-enable-the-rlf-process&quot;&gt;Using crouton to enable the RLF process&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is lots of info on the tubes about installing crouton. Google that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m using it because I really need Docker. I think. I can’t see how I’m going to get around the need to do something like nmap locally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this is a reasonable compromise. It’s way better than trying to run full VMs. Docker seems to do a bang up job with a tiny pile of compute resources so I am hoping it will make the tools I run with it feel snappy even on this light-weight box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, Docker is fun to use. I am finding some good use for it at work too.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://robie1373.github.io/robie,/hacking/2016/01/18/crouton-to-enable-RLF.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://robie1373.github.io/robie,/hacking/2016/01/18/crouton-to-enable-RLF.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Robie,</category>
        
        <category>hacking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>RLF: locally installed software</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;last edited&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;while-the-goal-is-to-have-almost-nothing-installed-on-the-local-machine-there-are-a-few-things-that-are-going-to-be-required-for-now-at-least-this-is-a-running-list-of-things-that-im-installing-locally-and-why&quot;&gt;While the goal is to have almost nothing installed on the local machine, there are a few things that are going to be required. For now at least. This is a running list of things that I’m installing locally and why.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;2016-01-18-setting-up-docker-on-chromebook&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;: Used to abstract away the ugly, dependency ridden, environment polluting and otherwise un-installable junk that I find myself using all the time. Like programming languages and network or security tools.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;2016-01-18-how-i-use-vim&quot;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt;: A dude’s got to edit.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;2016-01-18-crouton-to-enable-RLF&quot;&gt;Crouton&lt;/a&gt;: By default the CB doesn’t do Docker. Crouton allows you to run full Ubuntu (or other Linux) alongside ChromeOS. A bit heavy handed, but the best I could come up with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-things-that-take-time-on-the-local-box&quot;&gt;Other things that take time on the local box&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Generate and install ssh keys for various remote hosts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chrome Apps for Skype, Dropbox, an IRC. These are just web wrappers, so not really a local app. Also, they sync with the chrome profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://robie1373.github.io/robie,/hacking,/infrastructure/2016/01/18/RLF-locally-installed-software.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://robie1373.github.io/robie,/hacking,/infrastructure/2016/01/18/RLF-locally-installed-software.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Robie,</category>
        
        <category>hacking,</category>
        
        <category>infrastructure</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reducing local footprint</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;using-the-cloud-to-make-cheaper-laptops-viable&quot;&gt;Using the cloud to make cheaper laptops viable&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-laptop&quot;&gt;the laptop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ideal laptop has high quality intrinsic physical characteristics. That is to say the things which software can’t change. Keyboard, trackpad, screen. The things which interface with the fleshy parts of the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal is to reduce the cost of the laptop as much as possible (so I can quit buying MBP class hardware). There is a huge delta in price between an MBP and a low to midrange Chromebook. With that kind of budget I even can even afford to allocate some budget to VPS, cloud storage, or services which supplant the beefiness of the powerful laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;storage&quot;&gt;storage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This experiment puts a lot of reliance on the cloud services being always available. Or at least available all the time I need them. There is a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the storage front I may consider hedging somewhat and using some SAN storage at home to backup / cache cloud content. Honestly, that’s just prudent. However, it does change the cost calculus of the experiment somewhat. That said, a large percentage of the target audience already runs some sort of storage solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;local-apps---containers&quot;&gt;local apps -&amp;gt; containers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the part that I feel has really enabled this experiment. There are some apps that just need to be local. I have never been able to run a machine without installing a few hundred things regardless of what cloud-thingies I am running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That also means anytime I want to switch machines (whether for a conference, travel, repairs, upgrade, whatever) I have to spend the first 100 hours setting it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some tools exist to streamline the process like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lra/mackup&quot;&gt;Mackup&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/EvanPurkhiser/dots&quot;&gt;dots&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve tried them and they are great in their way. I never keep my environment up to date with them, though, so the benefit decreases as time increases. That’s me, not them I realize. There is a good chance that they will play a part in this experiment eventually, or things like them anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have recently started to set up containers for those tools I find myself reaching for often, especially the ones that are a PITA to install on a normal machine. Sometimes I have to do my job on a windows box too. At times like that the containers are absolutely critical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do a lot of code fumbling in a bunch of languages too. I don’t ever want to have to try to run a language I like in windows again. Those have to go into containers or get offloaded to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;local-apps-to-web-apps&quot;&gt;local apps to web apps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all apps need to be / can be / should be run in containers. Some of them will be replaced with the web version. Email is the classic example. Nothing new here. Just one of the tools that make the experiment seem feasible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;local-apps-to-aws-et-al&quot;&gt;local apps to AWS et al&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the second piece of the puzzle that has changed recently. Cloud compute resources have gotten &lt;em&gt;cheap&lt;/em&gt;. Most of my development has already moved to VPS type providers. I set up a reasonably sized host in AWS and have spent the time setting up all my tools there. I have moved to VIM for an editor. (This is not a polemic statement. Use emacs if you want to, just don’t bother me about it). One of the main reasons I did that was so I could run my editor-of-choice over ssh. That ought to remove the last reason I used to have for relapsing into ‘local dev’ habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep many of my dotfiles in github as well as my .vim. That’s not strictly necessary if I am strict about using the AWS box. I’m not sure I need to chisel that rule into the stone, though. I’m going to see what costs and benefits there are to being flexible about where code gets written or edited. The rule I am likely to enforce early on is that no development environments get installed locally. I seem to have a problem with that so I think its cold turkey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wrap-up&quot;&gt;wrap up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s the idea. I’m going to be keeping notes and stuff here so I don’t forget how to start by the time I finish. Again. Like I always do. If this helps you then super!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://robie1373.github.io/hacking,/infrastructure/2016/01/17/reducing_local_footprint.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://robie1373.github.io/hacking,/infrastructure/2016/01/17/reducing_local_footprint.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>hacking,</category>
        
        <category>infrastructure</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
